我们不能离开
We're not leaving.
此地不宜久留
We can't stay here.
万一还有狙击手呢
What if there's another sniper?
木板可挡不住子弹
A wood pallet won't stop one of those rounds.
我们连出去都不行
We can't even go outside.
至少白天不行
Not in the daylight.
瑞克说不逃 那我们就不逃
Rick says we're not running, we're not running.
好么 好死不如赖活着
No, better to live like rats.
你有何高见
You got a better idea?
依我看 咱们昨晚如果溜出去
Yeah, we should have slid out of here last night.
还能苟活几天
and lived to fight another day.
但已错过机会 不是吗
But we lost that window, didn't we?
现在外面肯定到处都是他的手下
I'm sure he's got scouts on every road out of this place by now.
我们才不怕那个变态
We ain't scared of that prick.
你们应该怕
Y'all should be.
那天安排卡车冲过围栏
That truck through the fence thing,
不过是给我们点厉害瞧瞧
that's just him ringing the doorbell.
即使我们有坚固的堡垒
We might have some thick walls to hide behind,
也敌不过他的武器和人马
but he's got the guns and the numbers.
一旦他占领了附近的高地
And if he takes the high ground around this place,
那就完了 他想饿死我们都可以
shoot, he could just starve us out if he wanted to.
把他关到别的牢笼去
Let's put him in the other cell block.
别急 他说的有道理
No. He's got a point.
都怪你 全是你惹的
This is all you. You started this.
现在不是追究责任的时候 关键是怎么办
What difference whose fault it is? What do we do?
我觉得我们应该离开
I said we should leave.
阿克塞尔死了
Now Axel's dead.
我们不能坐以待毙
We can't just sit here.
你给我回来
Get back here!
瑞克 你状态越来越糟
You're slipping, Rick.
我们都看到了 我们也理解
We've all seen it. We understand why.
但现在不是时候
But now is not the time.
你曾说别想要民主
You once said this isn't a democracy.
现在你必须身体力行
Now you have to own up to that.
我将一家老小的性命交予你手中
I put my family's life in your hands.
所以振作起来
So get your head clear.
拿出点行动来
and do something.
你不应该出来
You shouldn't be out here.
我枪法不赖
I'm a good shot.
的确
Yes, you are.
老爸
Hey, Dad?
怎么
Yeah?
我说句话 你能保证不生气吗
If I say something, will you promise not to be mad?
我不会生气
I won't get mad.
你不该继续了
You should stop.
继续什么
Stop what?
做我们的首领
Being the leader.
让赫谢尔和达里尔来吧
Let Hershel and Daryl handle things.
你应该歇一歇
You deserve a rest.
《行尸走肉》
现在有多少人了
How many does that give us now?
20个 还有些人患慢性疾病
20. We have several people with chronic conditions,
听觉障碍 关节炎
hearing impairments, arthritis.
如果加上他们 共26人
Adding those gives us 26.
那把13岁以上的全加上呢
And if we include men and women age 13 and up?
连孩子也算上吗
You mean boys and girls?
应该是青少年 用这个词更妙
Adolescence… it's a 20th century invention.
现在一共多少
Men and women.
35人
Uh, 35.
给他们都配好武器和弹药
Well, make sure they all have sidearms and plenty of ammo.
马丁内斯就绪后 就开始训练
We'll start training when Martinez is ready.
请进
Well, come in.
我听说了监狱的事 怎么回事
What's this I hear about the prison?
你说过你不会去骚扰他们的
You said you were gonna leave it alone.
不会报复他们
No retaliation.
我是去谈判的
I went to negotiate.
大门外有那么多行尸就够糟了
Bad enough we got biters at our gates.
不能再添个只有数里间隔的侵略者
We can't have aggressors just miles away.
所以你是去打个善意的招呼吗
So you went and welcomed them to the neighborhood?
你知道他们对我们开火了吗
You know they shot at us?
我不知道你们在一起时他们是什么样子
I don't know who these people were when you were with them,
但是他们现在变了 变得残忍嗜杀
but they've changed. They're bloodthirsty.
你知道这事吗
You knew about this?
今天早上才知道
I was informed this morning.
我之前不知道
I didn't know.
不要把他牵扯进来
Don't drag him into it.
说得对 这是咱们俩之间的事
You're right. This is between you and me.
我真是烦透了 受够了你的谎言
I'm sick of this. Sick of the lies.
我不会眼睁睁看着
And I'm not gonna watch this town.
这个镇和我的朋友们相互残杀
and my friends gun each other down.
太晚了
Well, it's too late.
太晚了是什么意思
What do you mean it's too late?
我不知道你想要证明什么
I don't know what you're trying to prove,
适可而止吧
but enough is enough.
我要去看他们
I'm going to see them.
我来处理这件事
I'll work this out.
他们是我们的敌人
Well, they're hostile.
这些是我们全部体格健全的人
These are all the able-bodied people we have.
他们会装备武器 接受训练
They're gonna carry arms and receive training.
我们不会再被突然袭击了
We won't get caught sleeping again.
我只需要一辆车
One car, that is all I need.
路被堵住了
The roads are blocked.
我们都差点回不来
We barely made it back ourselves.
安德莉亚
Andrea.
你敢去监狱
You go to that prison,
就别回来了
you stay there.
诺亚只有14岁
Noah's only 14.
他还有哮喘
Okay? He has asthma.
跑不了十米就喘不过来气了
He can't run more than 10 yards before losing his breath.
要他能有什么用
What good is that to you?
总督让所有能拿枪的人
The Governor wants everyone who can hold a gun.
- 现在到市政厅前集合 - 不行
- in front of the town hall now. - No.
安德莉亚 你得制止这事
Andrea, you have to straighten this out.
他们想让诺亚去打仗
They want Noah to fight.
谁说要打仗了
Who's talking about fighting?
你应该教大家如何自卫
You're supposed to be teaching people to defend themselves,
而不是组建一支军队
not raising an army.
醒醒吧
Wake up.
自卫的唯一方法就是组建军队
The only way to defend ourselves is with an army.
仔细监视 眼睛睁大 脑袋放低
Take watch. Eyes open, head down.
广场上都是行尸
Field's filled with walkers.
没发现外面有狙击手
Didn't see any snipers out there,
但是玛姬要继续放哨
but we'll keep Maggie on watch.
我去哨塔
I'll get up in the guard tower,
消灭一半行尸
take out half them walkers,
你们趁机修补围栏
give these guys a chance to fix the fence.
或者开几辆车把巴士放好
Or use some of the cars to put the bus in place.
不用光子弹我们拿不下广场
We can't access the field without burning through our bullets.
我们困在这了 食物和弹药所剩无几
So we're trapped in here. There's barely any food or ammo.
以前就短缺过 会没事的
Been here before. We'll be all right.
那时候这里只有我们
That's when it was just us.
没有毒蛇混在我们中间
Before there was a snake in the nest.
老兄 还要再说一遍吗
Man, we gonna go through this again?
莫尔就住在这 他现在和我们一伙
Look, Merle's staying here. He's with us now.
- 习惯一下吧 - 嘿
- Get used to it. - Hey.
你们所有人都是
All y'all.
说真的 瑞克
Seriously, Rick,
我不认为莫尔可以住在这里
I don't think Merle living here is really gonna fly.
我不能把他赶出去
I can't kick him out.
肖恩试图杀你后 你会和他共处吗
I wouldn't ask you to live with Shane after he tried to kill you.
莫尔服过役
Merle has military experience.
他也许不守规则
He may be erratic,
但不要低估他对自己弟弟的忠诚
but don't underestimate his loyalty to his brother.
如果说有一举两得的办法呢
What if we solve both problems at once?
把莫尔交给总督 作为谈判砝码
Deliver Merle to the Governor. Bargaining chip.
交出他的叛徒 或许可以停战
Give him his traitor, maybe declare a truce.
你是那个农场主赫谢尔
You're the farmer Hershel.
那你一定是那个败类莫尔了
And you're the black sheep Merle.
你怎样失掉腿的
How'd you lose it?
我被咬了
I was bit.
被咬 你自己砍掉的
Bit? You hack it off yourself?
不
No.
瑞克砍的
Rick did.
真是大好人啊
Awful kindly of him.
救了我的命
Saved my life.
让我有更多时间陪伴女儿们
Gave me more time with my girls.
让你有更多的时间陪你弟弟
Gave you more time with your brother.
此恩无价
Can't put a price on that.
世道崩乱 还谈什么有价无价
Can't put a price on anything anymore.
我在其中一个牢房里
I found this.
找到这个
in one of the cells.
我不止很久没看过《圣经》了
Lost more than the Good Book there for a while.
我也迷失了方向
Lost my way.
「如果你的右手触犯了你
"And if your right hand offends you,
把它砍掉 扔的远远的
cut it off, cast it from you.
这是有益的抉择
For it is profitable.
因为其中一个必定消亡「
that one of your members should perish…"
「而不是你的整个身体坠入地狱」
"And not that thy whole body should be cast into hell."
《马太福音》第5章29至30段
Matthew 5:29 and 30.
伍德伯里有个超赞的图书馆
Woodbury had a damn fine library.
我所怀念的为数不多的东西
One of the only things I miss about it.
当总督再次来时
When the Governor returns,
他会先杀掉我
he's gonna kill me first.
之后是米琼恩 我弟弟
Michonne, my brother,
然后是你的女儿们
then your girls.
格伦 卡尔 还有那个婴儿
Glenn, Carl, the baby,
所有剩余的人
whoever else is left.
最后杀瑞克
He'll save Rick for last.
让他亲眼目睹家人和朋友的惨死
so he can watch his family and friends die ugly.
这就是你们要对付的人
That's who you're dealing with.
这是麦克劳德女士
This is Mrs. McLeod.
她有关节炎
She's the one with arthritis.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Well, thank you, dear,
我们会找到其他适合你的工作
but we'll find another way you can help us.
诺亚有哮喘
Noah's asthmatic.
孩子 你用过枪吗
You ever shoot a gun, son?
我有过一支BB手枪 被我妈妈没收了
I had a BB gun once. My mom took it away.
你在这里可以好好学习了
Well, you're gonna learn from the best.
还没来得及说很高兴你能回来
Haven't had a chance to say I'm glad you came back.
高兴什么 回到这烂地方
To what? All this?
这是我们的家
This is our home.
这是个坟墓
This is a tomb.
T仔也这么说
That's what T-Dog called it.
我原以为他是对的
Thought he was right.
直到你救了我
till you found me.
他虽然是你哥哥 但他对你是毒药
He's your brother, but he's not good for you.
不要让他影响到你
Don't let him bring you down.
毕竟 我们一起经历了这么多
After all, look how far you've come.
我们彻底封锁了大门
We sealed it thoroughly.
没人能进出
Nobody's getting in or out.
我想问你件事
I'm gonna ask you something.
需要你坦诚相对
and I need you to be honest.
好吧
Okay.
监狱的那场战斗
The fight at the prison,
你发誓什么也不知道吗
you swear you didn't know anything about it?
我不会提倡那么做的
I wouldn't advocate a move like that.
那纯属泄愤
It's just posturing.
很好 那你替我打掩护
Good. Then you have to cover for me.
我要去监狱
I'm going to the prison.
- 不能让总督知道 - 别去
- And the Governor can't know. - Don't.
我必须去 我曾是他们的一员
I have to. I was with them.
别逼我做两难抉择
Don't put me in this situation.
- 我也希望有其他办法 - 如果他发现了
- I wish there was another way. - If he finds out…
我们必须冒这个险
That's a chance we have to take.
你也许愿意冒 但我不
Maybe you do, but I don't.
抱歉 我做不到
I'm sorry. I can't.
看看现在的情况
Look at what's happened.
伍德伯里成了童兵军营
Woodbury is an armed camp with child soldiers.
他们成了毫无价值的炮灰
Cannon fodder in a war over what?
这难道是你科研的意义吗
Is that what all your work is for?
拜托 帮我溜出去
Please, help me get out of here.
我不能开车去 他们不会开门
I can't take a car. They won't open the gates.
我只需要溜出去
I just need to sneak out,
想办法到监狱 跟瑞克谈谈
make my way to the prison, and talk to Rick.
你这是背叛行为
This is a betrayal.
不 我是在阻止两败俱伤
No, it's an attempt to stop this before more people get killed.
你能帮我的 米尔顿
You can do this, Milton.
进来
Come in.
你让我监视她
You asked me to keep tabs on her.
没错
That's right.
她要溜回监狱
She's going back to the prison.
并要求我协助
and has requested my assistance in escaping.
「溜」是她的原话 不是我的
Her words, not mine.
协助她
Help her.
好吧 你是真要我协助
Okay, do you really want me to do that,
还是在测试我
or is this some sort of test?
既然她要求
if she asks for help,
你就协助
help her.
米尔顿
Milton.
好样的
Good work.
喂 你
Hey, you!
糟了 安德莉亚
Oh, shit. Andrea!
按住它
Pin it down.
别让它起来
Don't let it up.
再多撑一会儿
Just a little more.
把它头抬起来
Lift its head.
按下去
Force it down.
稳住它
Hey, hold it! Hold it!
我在努力
I'm trying.
当心
Watch out.
好了
All right.
我们能赶紧完事吗
Can we finish this up, please?
我来 我来
I got it. I got it.
健身是好事
Smart to stay fit.
有氧训练益处多
Don't leave out the cardio.
如果我们要同住一个屋檐下
You know, if we're gonna live under the same roof,
我们应该把话说清
we should clear the air.
追杀你那件事
This whole hunting you down thing,
我只是公事公办
that was just business.
执行命令
Carrying out orders.
就像盖世太保
Hmm. Like the Gestapo.
没错 正是
Yeah. Exactly.
我做过很多亏心事
I've done a lot of things I ain't proud of.
末世前后都做过
Before and after.
不管怎样 但愿你能尽释前嫌
Anyway, hope we can get past it.
既往不咎
Let bygones be bygones.
这就像迷彩
It's a diversionary tactic.
能分散行尸注意力
It keeps the walkers away.
那它们俩怎么照来不误
Didn't work so well with those two.
你们有营地吗
You got a camp?
只有我们俩
It's just us.
我们有座镇子 高墙环绕
We have a town. It's walled.
大概有七十个人
There's about 70 of us.
你们还收新人吗
You take people in?
是的
We do.
- 我来带他们回去 - 你确定吗
- I'll take them back. - Are you sure?
- 如果他问起来… - 我会处理的
- If he asks, just… - I'll handle it.
比起他们来 我更会和总督打交道
I'm better with him than I am with them.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
我们这几天历尽磨难
We've had a rough couple of days.
- 你要去哪里 - 继续巡视
- Where you going? - Got to finish my run.
一个人吗
By yourself?
我没事
I'll be fine.
我的守护神在呢
Got my guardian angel here.
- 需要帮忙吗 - 不用
- Need any help? - Nope.
我可以的
I'm good.
那边好像不大对劲
Psst Something weird out there.
是安德莉亚
Andrea.
去叫你爸爸和其他人来
Get your dad and the others.
前进
Go.
安全
Clear!
- 只有你一个人吗 - 开门
- Are you alone? - Open the gate.
只有你一个人吗
Are you alone?!
瑞克
Rick!
开门
Open it.
举起手 转过身去
Hands up! Turn around.
- 什么 - 赶快转过身
- What? - Turn around now!
给我趴在地上
Get down on the floor.
我问你是不是一个人
I asked if you were alone.
是的
I am.
欢迎回家
Welcome back.
起来
Get up.
你救了我之后 我们以为你死了
After you saved me, we thought you were dead.
赫谢尔 天啊
Hershel, my God.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
肖恩呢
Where's Shane?
洛莉呢
And Lori?
洛莉生了个女孩 可她自己没能活下来
She had a girl. Lori didn't survive.
T仔也死了
Neither did T-Dog.
太遗憾了
I'm so sorry.
卡尔
Carl.
瑞克 我…
Rick, I…
你们都住在这里吗
You all live here?
这里还有牢房里
Here and the cell block.
那边吗
There?
我可以进去吗
Well, can I go in?
我不允许
I won't allow that.
我不是敌人 瑞克
I'm not an enemy, Rick.
广场和院子本来很安全
We had that field and courtyard.
直到你男友开着卡车毁掉了围栏
until your boyfriend tore down the fence.
还开枪扫射我们
with a truck and shot us up.
他说是你先开火的
He said you fired first.
他在说谎
Well, he's lying.
他杀死了一个幸存的犯人
He killed an inmate who survived in here.
我们都喜欢他 他是我们的一员
We liked him. He was one of us.
我一点都不知情
I didn't know anything about that.
我一知道就马上赶来了
As soon as I found out, I came.
直到枪战爆发后
I didn't even know you were in Woodbury.
我才知道你们来到了伍德伯里
until after the shoot-out.
那是几天前的事了
That was days ago.
我告诉你了 我尽快赶来了
I told you, I came as soon as I could.
- 你跟他们说了什么 - 什么都没说
- What have you told them? - Nothing.
我不懂了 我曾和你们一起离开亚特兰大
I don't get it. I left Atlanta with you people.
现在却被排斥在外
and now I'm the odd man out?
他差点杀了米琼恩 还可能杀死我们
He almost killed Michonne and he would have killed us.
是他拿着枪啊
With his finger on the trigger.
难道不是他绑架了你吗
Isn't he the one who kidnapped you?
还殴打你吗
Who beat you?
听着
Look,
我无法为菲利普的所作所为找借口或解释
I cannot excuse or explain what Philip has done.
但我来这里就是为了解决僵局
But I am here trying to bring us together.
我们必须消除分歧
We have to work this out.
没什么分歧
There's nothing to work out.
我们会杀了他
We're gonna kill him.
我不知道怎么杀 何时杀 但我们会的
I don't know how or when, but we will.
我们可以解决此事
We can settle this.
伍德伯里欢迎你们定居
There is room at Woodbury for all of you.
你还真是有「切身体会」
You know better than that.
你凭什么认为总督会谈判
What makes you think this man wants to negotiate?
他亲口说了吗
Did he say that?
没
No.
那你为什么来这里
Then why did you come here?
因为他正在备战
Because he's gearing up for war.
镇民很惊恐 他们把你们当成杀人魔
The people are terrified. They see you as killers.
他们在训练 准备进攻
They're training to attack.
我看这样吧 下次你见到菲利普
I'll tell you what. Next time you see Philip,
告诉他 另一只眼睛我要定了
you tell him I'm gonna take his other eye.
我们忍气吞声太久了
We're taken too much shit for too long.
他想开战 放马过来
He wants a war? He's got one.
瑞克
Rick.
如果你不冷静地解决问题
If you don't sit down and try to work this out,
我不知道会发生什么
I don't know what's gonna happen.
他有一城镇的人
He has a whole town.
看看你们
Look at you.
你们已经失去了太多
You've lost so much already.
你们不能再孤立无援了
You can't stand alone anymore.
如果你真想帮我们 就引我们进镇
You want to make this right, get us inside.
- 不行 - 那就没什么好说了
- No. - Then we got nothing to talk about.
镇里有无辜的百姓
There are innocent people.
你误导了他们
You poisoned them.
我只是告诉了他们真相
I just told them the truth.
我没有选他而放弃你
I didn't choose him over you.
我想要正常生活
I wanted a life.
而我们一进伍德伯里 你就充满敌意
Once we entered Woodbury, you became hostile.
- 那是因为我能看清 - 看清什么
- That's 'cause I could see it. - See what?
（从你看到他那一刻 就被迷住了心窍）
- 这不是真的 - 你依然执迷不悟
- That is not true. - And you still are.
不 我留下是因为镇民需要我
No, I am there because those people need me.
那这里的人怎么办
And what about these people?
我也在试着救他们
I'm trying to save them, too.
我真不知道救世主情结还会传染
I did not realize the messiah complex was contagious.
去死吧 米琼恩
Go to hell, Michonne.
他派莫尔追杀我
He sent Merle to kill me.
如果你跟我一起走 他也会杀了你
Would have sent him to kill you, too, if you had come with me.
但你没走 不是吗
But you didn't, did you?
你为了舒适的床而抛弃了朋友
You chose a warm bed over a friend.
这就是我回伍德伯里的原因
That's why I went back to Woodbury.
我要揭穿他的本来面目
Exposed him for what he is.
我知道真相会伤害你
I knew that it would hurt you.
斯蒂文斯医生马上就来为你们检查
Dr. Stevens will be here soon. We'll get you checked over.
- 谢谢 - 我的荣幸
- Thank you. - It's my pleasure.
你们想住多久都行
Now you're welcome to stay as long as you like.
我们有食物 干净衣物 热水
We got food, fresh clothing, hot water.
通常我们还会
Normally we'd provide you.
给你们武器和车辆以备上路
with weapons and a car for your journey,
但现在我们没有富余
but we need all we have.
你们看起来在备战
Looks like you're battening down the hatches.
你们被攻击了吗
Were you guys attacked?
是的 但不是被行尸 而是一群恶徒
Yeah, but not by biters. Some dangerous people out there.
他们几天前攻击了我们
They came at us a few days ago.
没人受伤吧
Anyone hurt?
有些伤亡
There were several fatalities.
- 该死 抱歉 - 是啊
- Damn. Sorry. - Yeah.
这世道得加倍小心
Can't be too careful these days.
你们能上路后 最好去西边
When you're ready to travel, head west.
别去85号公路以北就行
Avoid anything north up 85.
我们刚从那边来
We just came from there.
在一个监狱里撞见个疯子
Ran into some whack-job in a prison.
你见过他
You saw him?
可不是 像个白痴似的乱叫
Oh, yeah. Screaming like an idiot.
他有点精神错乱
He's a little unhinged.
可是其他人看起来都不错
But the others seemed decent.
那个首领回来前都相安无事
Everything seemed cool until their leader came back.
他一回来就拿枪指着我鼻子
and practically shoved a gun in my face.
你们去过监狱
You were at the prison?
我们进去避难 艾伦的妻子死了
We went in for shelter. Lost Allen's wife.
那个叫瑞克的人突然出现 把我们赶走
This guy Rick showed up all of sudden, chased us out.
需要帮忙收拾他们吗 把我们算上
You need help with these guys? We're in.
现在 不
Well, now, no…
我们不该让你们参与我们的战斗
we couldn't ask you to join in our fight.
听着 我们不想离开这里
Look, we don't want to be out there.
在外面我们迟早会…
It's only a matter of time before…
不 我理解
No, I understand.
只要能留下 我们做什么都行
Whatever we got to do to earn our keep.
你们到过监狱内部吗
Were you inside the prison?
你能描述一下它的布局吗
Can you describe the layout?
挺难形容的 不过我尽量吧
It's pretty confusing, but I could try.
你们先好好休息
You get your rest.
我们可以明天再谈这个
We can talk about it tomorrow.
如我所说 你们想留多久都行
As I say, you're welcome to stay here as long as you like.
今晚你们先休息 商量一下
But you take the night. Talk it over.
晚安
Good night.
你可不能不跟小拽女打个招呼就走啊
You can't leave without meeting Little Ass-Kicker.
我能抱抱她吗
May I hold her?
- 当然可以 - 哦
- Of course. - Oh.
- 抱住了吗 - 抱住了
- Got her? - I got her.
小可爱
Oh, look at you.
我猜
Let me guess.
小拽女这名是达里尔起的
Daryl named her "Ass-Kicker."
那不是她的真名
That's not really her name.
- 朱迪思 - 朱迪思
- Judith. - Judith.
你好 朱迪思
Hi, Judith.
你是多么珍贵啊
Oh, how precious are you?
洛莉出了什么事
What happened to Lori?
死于剖腹产
During a C-section.
玛姬
Maggie.
- 卡尔不得不… - 我的天啊
- Carl had to… - Oh, my God.
T仔死于我脱险
T-Dog died leading me to safety.
那肖恩呢
And Shane?
瑞克杀了他
Rick killed him.
我们离开农场的那晚
The night we left the farm.
兰德尔事件完全是个骗局
That whole Randall thing was a lie.
肖恩试图杀死瑞克
Shane tried to kill Rick.
肖恩是爱瑞克的
Shane loved Rick.
肖恩也爱洛莉
Shane loved Lori.
瑞克变得冷血
Rick's become cold.
喜怒无常
Unsteady.
他有他的原因
He has his reasons.
总督那 你得花点心思
The Governor, you need to do something.
我会的
I am.
你要和他上床
No, you need to sleep with him.
给他一生中最消魂的一夜
Give him the greatest night of his life.
让他放松警惕
You get him to drop his guard.
等他睡着了 你就可以终结这一切
Then when he's sleeping, you can end this. Thanks.
这车我能开走吗
Can you spare it?
可以
Yeah.
好了 保重
Well, take care.
安德莉亚
Andrea.
小心点
Be careful.
你也是
You, too.
快走
Go!
注意了
Heads up!
快蹲下
Hey, get down.
快停车
That's far enough.
举起手来
Hands up.
我去监狱了
I went to the prison.
他们溃不成军
They're broken,
处境十分糟糕
living in horrible conditions.
米琼恩在那儿吧
Michonne there?
莫尔呢
Merle?
是的
Yes.
还有瑞克
And Rick?
对
Yes.
是他派你回来的吧
He send you back here?
不
No.
我自己要回来的
That was my call.
为什么
Why?
因为你属于这里
'Cause you belong here.
∮ 有人在我们镇上竖起块牌子 ∮
∮ They hung a sign up in our town ∮
∮ 如果你快活度日 便不会忘掉耻辱 ∮
∮ If you live it up, you won't live it down ∮
∮ 于是她离开了蒙特里欧 孩子 ∮
∮ So she left Monte Rio, son ∮
∮ 就像一颗子弹离开枪膛 ∮
∮ Just like a bullet leaves a gun ∮
∮ 带着深灰色的眼睛和梦露般的臀部 ∮
∮ With charcoal eyes and Monroe hips ∮
∮ 她走了 踏上了去往加州的旅程 ∮
∮ She went and took the California trip ∮
∮ 那晚月亮如金 她的头发似风 ∮
∮ Well, the moon was gold and her hair like wind ∮
∮ 她说 别回头 ∮
∮ Said don't look back now ∮
∮ 跟我走 吉姆 ∮
∮ Just come on, Jim ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on Hold on ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on ∮
∮ 握着我的手 我就站在这儿 ∮
∮ Take my hand, I'm standing right here ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on ∮
∮ 他曾给过她一块廉价手表 ∮
∮ Well, he gave her a dime-store watch ∮
∮ 和一枚用勺子打造的戒指 ∮
∮ And a ring made from a spoon ∮
∮ 每个人都在寻找替罪羊 ∮
∮ Everyone's looking for someone to blame ∮
∮ 当你与我同眠 你便与我同姓… ∮
∮ If you share my bed, you share my name… ∮
总算重聚了啊
Some reunion, huh?
她左右两难
She's in a jam.
我们都是
We all are.
安德莉亚说得在理
Andrea's persuasive.
总督全副武装
This fella's armed to the teeth.
决心干掉我们
Bent on destruction.
那你打算怎样
So what do you want to do?
我们也得准备
We match it.
我要出去一趟
I'm going on a run.
我明天出去
I'll head out tomorrow.
不 你留下
No, you stay here.
盯着你哥哥
Keep an eye on your brother.
我很高兴你回来了 真的
I'm glad you're back, really,
但如果他惹事了 你得负责
but if he causes a problem, it's on you.
我会看好他的
I got him.
我和米琼恩一起去
I'll take Michonne.
你确定这是好主意吗
You sure that's a good idea?
试了就知道了
I'll find out.
还有卡尔
And Carl.
他已经准备好了
He's ready.
你管好这里
You hold it down here.
没问题
You got it.
∮ 这儿已没有什么令你留恋 ∮
∮ When there's nothing left to keep you here ∮
∮ 当你被这个忧郁世界所弃 ∮
∮ When you're falling behind in this big blue world ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on Hold on ∮
∮ 你得坚持住啊 握着我的手 ∮
∮ Got to hold on Take my hand, ∮
∮ 我就站在这儿 你得坚持住… ∮
∮ I'm standing right here Got to hold on… ∮
∮ 来到河畔旅馆 ∮
∮ Down by the Riverside Motel ∮
∮ 一角钱掉下 ∮
∮ It's 10 below and falling ∮
∮ 一个一元店 ∮
∮ By a 99-cent store ∮
∮ 她闭上眼开始摇摆 ∮
∮ She closed her eyes and started swaying ∮
∮ 但很难跳起来 ∮
∮ But it's so hard to dance that way ∮
∮ 天是那么冷，还没有音乐 ∮
∮ When it's cold and there's no music ∮
∮ 你的老家已远去 ∮
∮ Well, your old hometown is so far away ∮
∮ 但在你心里，一张唱片 ∮
∮ But inside your head there's a record ∮
∮ 正在播放着一首歌 ∮
∮ That's playing a song called ∮
∮ 坚持住 坚持住 ∮
∮ Hold on, hold on ∮
∮ 宝贝 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ Baby, you got to hold on ∮
∮ 握着我的手 我就站在这儿 ∮
∮ Take my hand, I'm standing right there ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on, hold on ∮
∮ 宝贝 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ Baby, got to hold on ∮
∮ 握着我的手 我就站在这儿 ∮
∮ Take my hand, I'm standing right there ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on, hold on ∮
∮ 宝贝 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ Baby, you got to hold on ∮
∮ 握着我的手 我就站在这儿 ∮
∮ And take my hand, I'm standing right here ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 宝贝 ∮
∮ You got to hold on, baby ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 女孩 ∮
∮ You got to hold on, girl ∮
∮ 你得坚持住 ∮
∮ You got to hold on ∮
∮ You got to hold on. ∮